<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sugardrum</title>
    <description>Sugardrum create folk/indie storytelling songs with beautiful vocals, fingerpicking acoustic guitar, cello, electronica and percussion.</description>
    <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.sugardrum.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 20:18:36 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2017 20:18:36 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>BBC 6music and other unexpected things</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Things have been a bit quiet on the music front in my life recently while I’ve been busy being a Dad, doing the day job and training to run the London Marathon.  I am however, finding time to work on some of the song ideas I’ve been writing in the odd moment over the past few months and am excited over the prospect of new songs on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bbc-6music&quot;&gt;BBC 6Music&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unexpected things have also been happening. Last Saturday I had a nice surprise when I heard Tom Robinson play my song &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4pM6WphmRhQ&quot;&gt;Postcard&lt;/a&gt; again on his show on BBC Radio 6Music.  He introduced Sugardrum as:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“a gorgeous project of multi instrumentalist Nigel Bunner”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can listen to the show for the next week on the BBC website at:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b08lphyq#play&quot;&gt;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b08lphyq#play&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;festival-news&quot;&gt;Festival news&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My &lt;a href=&quot;/gigs/&quot;&gt;gigs&lt;/a&gt; page is currently looking a bit scarce as this has been the first year when I’ve not actively pursued any summer festival dates. This was so I could spend more time with my family and work on some new songs. It was a nice then to be asked to play at Tribal Earth festival down in Sussex towards the end of August. This is a lovely little festival that I’ve performed at a few times before, so I gladly accepted their invite to come and play. The festival is on the 17th-20th August and more details of the location and where I’m playing will be on the gigs page nearer the time. If any other surprise gigs come along in the meantime I’ll add them on there too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 10:38:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2017/04/09/bbc-6music-and-other-unexpected-things/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2017/04/09/bbc-6music-and-other-unexpected-things/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Countdown to Christmas - Have Yourself a Merry Little Christmas acoustic cover</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the lead up to Christmas I'm posting a track each day this week from my EP of Christmas Covers. First up is my acoustic cover of &quot;Have Yourself a Merry Little Christmas&quot;.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 100%; height: 120px;&quot; src=&quot;https://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=105776390/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/tracklist=false/artwork=small/track=3939976386/transparent=true/&quot; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/merry-christmas&quot;&gt;Merry Christmas by Sugardrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/pages/sugardrum/289395918859&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/sugardrummusic&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; pages for posts about the other tracks all this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All 6 tracks are available to download at a &amp;quot;name your price&amp;quot; from my shop on Bandcamp.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe style=&quot;border: 0; width: 290px; height: 654px;&quot; src=&quot;http://bandcamp.com/EmbeddedPlayer/album=105776390/size=large/bgcol=ffffff/linkcol=0687f5/transparent=true/&quot; seamless&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/merry-christmas&quot;&gt;Merry Christmas by Sugardrum&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 19:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/12/19/countdown-to-christmas-have-yourself-merry-little-christmas-cover/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/12/19/countdown-to-christmas-have-yourself-merry-little-christmas-cover/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Short story book, For You I Hide this, now available on Kindle</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The book of short stories I wrote to accompany my album Postcards is now available on the Amazon Kindle store. It's free if you're a Kindle Unlimited member or just &amp;pound;2.45 if you're not.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;div class=&quot;iframe-cont&quot;&gt;
&lt;iframe type=&quot;text/html&quot; width=&quot;336&quot; height=&quot;550&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen style=&quot;max-width:100%&quot; src=&quot;https://read.amazon.co.uk/kp/card?asin=B01N3OBT3W&amp;preview=inline&amp;linkCode=kpe&amp;ref_=cm_sw_r_kb_dp_3ankybVAW6FVY&quot; &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;For you I hide This&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A fascinating collection of twelve short stories drawn from Nigel’s experiences and imagination. A magical trail under the stairs offers a glimpse into a future self, the hidden words written on postcards on a wall, a cat who tries to break free from its natural instinct to eat everything that moves, the joy of taking the day off to play in a snow covered landscape and the heartfelt tale of living with dementia. Each story is based on a song from Nigel's debut album Postcards performing as indie folk artist Sugardrum.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to change the name of the book from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/&quot;&gt;limited edition print version&lt;/a&gt;. It's now called &amp;quot;For you I hide this&amp;quot; after one of the lines in the song Postcard. The old title used for the print version, &amp;quot;Postcard Stories&amp;quot; I realised was the same as a type of story written to fit on a postcard. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which there are still a few copies of the print version of the book available &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/&quot;&gt;free with my album&lt;/a&gt;, but hurry, as there aren't many left.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 21:05:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/11/12/short-story-book-for-you-i-hide-this-available-on-kindle/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/11/12/short-story-book-for-you-i-hide-this-available-on-kindle/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Poppies video</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I've just uploaded a new video for my song Poppies that I made earlier in the week. The song features on my current album, &lt;a href=&quot;/listen/&quot;&gt;Postcards&lt;/a&gt; and confused one reviewer who thought it was just about being lonely. I always thought the words spoke for themselves, especially with the title Poppies, but to avoid confusion the song is about peace and the lonelines that accompanies the aftermath of hostile conflict.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;In my mind I pictured the protagonists walking through a war torn and deserted land, passing abandoned and half destroyed houses. I went through many different ideas for the video but decided to avoid using any war footage and instead went for something that complimented the gentle mood of the music, using lots of different aerial footage with the lyrics over the top.&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4okWyNdSkc4&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 11 Nov 2016 19:47:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/11/11/new-video-poppies/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/11/11/new-video-poppies/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Summer festival news</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I meant to write a blog post a couple of months ago about taking a little break from things before becoming a Dad, but I've been too busy to write anything until now. Moving house also added to the extra busyness. I have just found a brief moment of time at 1:54am so here goes...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm about to become a Dad... no hang on...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I became a Dad to a beautiful baby girl just over 2 months ago. Life has been both wonderful and frantically busy ever since. As a result I'm going to be doing less gigs this summer. I've not contacted my usual contacts about performing at Glastonbury or Edinburgh festivals this year, but I am still playing at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tribalearth.co.uk&quot; title=&quot;Tribal Earth Fesitval&quot;&gt;Tribal Earth festival&lt;/a&gt; down in Sussex. It's a lovely small festy on the weekend of the 20th August that raises funds for a children's charity in Kathmandu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm playing at 5:50pm on the Saturday and might even bring the little one along on backing vocals :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I found a nice review of my 3 Penny Postcard EP the other day in a print magazine called Apollo Has Landed&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Sugardrum is the kind of one man band that the record industy keeps trying to make in a lab. His low key, mellow acoustic offerings are touching, poignant in their sparing use of lyrics and moving when singer Nigel Bunner does give voice to his uncomplicated, sentimental lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whilst there are elements of folk to his mainly acoustic music, it’s hard to pin it down to a genre, not that you would want to. Electronica sits comfortably next to cello and the whole thing washes out of the speakers as a single, inseperable sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His latest EP 3 Penny Postcards is almost impossible to list to without wishing it was at least twice the length it is. His reserved style calls to mind Nick Drake and his deft handling of subjects rarely covered in pop music (dementia, anyone?) should be a challenge to all other singer songwriters to raise their game.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Appolo Has Landed print magazine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2016 04:41:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/07/12/summer-fesitval-news/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/07/12/summer-fesitval-news/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New short story book to go with the Postcards album</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I've written a book of short stories called &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/postcards&quot;&gt;Postcard Stories&lt;/a&gt; to accompany my new album, Postcards, with each story being about a song from the album. It's 90 pages long and there are limited edition print copies available free with the album, or the album is free with the book, whichever you prefer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The themes range from the fantastical – a magical trail under the stairs offering a glimpse into a future self, the hidden words written on postcards on a wall, a cat who trying to break free from its natural instinct to eat everything that moves – or the real world joy of taking the day off to play in a snow covered landscape. There are a couple of childrens stories in there too and a hidden object connecting several of the stories together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found some of them easier to write than others as many of my songs are stories in themselves. It sometimes just took a little longer to extend the story in the song into something that would work for a short story on the page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both the CD and the book are now available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/postcards&quot;&gt;Sugardrum shop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;a href=&quot;http://files.sugardrum.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/postcards-book-and-album.jpg&quot; class=&quot;group fresco&quot; data-fresco-group=&quot;blog_photos&quot; data-fresco-group=&quot;shared_options&quot;&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;alignleft size-thumbnail&quot; src=&quot;http://files.sugardrum.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/postcards-book-and-album-150x150.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Apr 2016 13:41:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/04/24/postcards-short-story-book/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/04/24/postcards-short-story-book/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Motorway Song played on Tom Robinson's BBC 6music mixtape show</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Motorway Song, from the new album &lt;a href=&quot;/listen/&quot;&gt;Postcards&lt;/a&gt; was played on Tom Robinson's mixtape show on BBC 6music last night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can listen to the show again by following the link below&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/b0761jmt&quot;&gt;BBC 6music Introducing Mixtape: 11/04/2016&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There's also been some more lovely reviews of the new album &lt;a href=&quot;/listen/&quot;&gt;Postcards&lt;/a&gt;. Here's an extract from one by The Crack magazine&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;&amp;hellip;his debut album does not spare the good stuff. He’s one of those classic, finger-picking guitar types – think Nick Drake – and exudes a warmth that amps up the togs to fleecy levels.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; &lt;a title=&quot; Sugardrum - The Crack Magazine&quot; href=&quot;http://www.thecrackmagazine.com/view-editorial/3426&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Crack Magazine&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2016 13:41:02 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/04/11/motorway-song-played-on-bbc-6music/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/04/11/motorway-song-played-on-bbc-6music/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Sugardrum album Postcards and Postcard video</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It's a beautiful sunny day, prerfect for the release of my new album, Postcards. To celebrate here is a new video I made of the song Postcard from the album.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;youtube-container&quot;&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/4pM6WphmRhQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There have been some lovely reviews of the album already...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Fans of Nick Drake will love this&amp;hellip; He has that feel and tone that Drake used major/minor chord progressions to create and he also transforms it into something all the more beautiful with delicate moving harmonies.&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Alex Gallacher, &lt;a title=&quot;Folk Radio: Sugardrum&quot; href=&quot;http://www.folkradio.co.uk/2016/03/video-premiere-postcard-by-sugardrum/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Folkradio.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;Gentle folk musings on impressive debut&amp;hellip; gentle and melodic bearing more than a passing resemblance to the much missed Nick Drake&amp;#8221; &amp;#8211; Michael Farley, &lt;a title=&quot;Americana-uk: Sugardrum&quot; href=&quot;https://www.americana-uk.com/cdreviews/item/sugardrum-postcards&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Americana-uk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 17:45:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/03/25/new-sugardrum-album-postcards-and-postcard-video/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/03/25/new-sugardrum-album-postcards-and-postcard-video/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New Sugardrum album Postcards and 12th March gig at Gallery Cafe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The CDs of my new album arrived in the post this week. The album is called Postcards and has been nearly 4 years in the making. During that time various things in my life meant I had to put the album on hold for a bit. Recording and releasing an album entirely yourself takes a lot of work, epseically when you're doing all the recording, mixing and designing of the artwork yourself and I just didn't have the time to finish it to a level I felt the songs deserved.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;Instead, I released an EP in December 2013 called the &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/3-penny-postcard&quot;&gt;3 Penny Postcard&lt;/a&gt; EP which featured some of the songs destined for the album that I had finished, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/forgotten-remixed&quot;&gt;Forgotten remixed&lt;/a&gt; EP featuring 4 remixes I'd made of my song Forgotten in July 2015 and an &lt;a href=&quot;http://shop.sugardrum.com/album/merry-christmas&quot;&gt;EP of Christmas Covers&lt;/a&gt;. I also carried on gigging and working on the other recordings when I had time.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;The meaning of some of the songs have evolved during that time resulting in a more fuller and honest album than if I had finished it 3 years ago as originally planned.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;p&gt;The album will be available on &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/gb/album/postcards/id1081336392&quot;&gt;iTunes&lt;/a&gt;, Amazon, Spotify etc and from the Sugardrum online shop from 25th March. You can buy the CD version which comes in a full colour digisleeve packaging complete with lyrics booklet via the Sugardrum shop from that date, or come to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.songkick.com/concerts/26076173-sugardrum-at-gallery-cafe&quot;&gt;launch gig on 12th March&lt;/a&gt; at the Gallery Cafe where I'll have copies for sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;photos&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;group fresco&quot; data-fresco-group=&quot;sugardrum_photos&quot; data-fresco-group-options=&quot;ui: 'inside'&quot; title=&quot;New Sugardrum EP - Postcards&quot; href=&quot;http://files.sugardrum.com/img/blog-photos/2016/02/sugardrum-postcards-cd.jpg&quot; rel=&quot;group&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://files.sugardrum.com/img/blog-photos/2016/02/sugardrum-postcards-cd-thumb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;New Sugardrum EP - Postcards&quot; width=&quot;150&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I'm also in the middle of writing a book of short stories, each one about a song from the album which will be available as a limited edition book. More on that nearer the release date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2016 21:40:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/02/27/new-sugardrum-album-postcards-and-12th-march-gig-at-gallery-cafe/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/02/27/new-sugardrum-album-postcards-and-12th-march-gig-at-gallery-cafe/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>New York New York cover featured on French website Cover and Remix</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just before the weekend French blog &lt;a href=&quot;http://reprise-me.wix.com/cover-and-remix#!New-york-New-york/comz/551681ff0cf21933cd1bd8ce&quot;&gt;Cover and Remix&lt;/a&gt; featured my cover of New York New York. Here's a link to their website and a reminder of the video I also made for the song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://reprise-me.wix.com/cover-and-remix#!New-york-New-york/comz/551681ff0cf21933cd1bd8ce&quot;&gt;New York New York cover by Sugardrum on Cover and Remix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9&quot;&gt;
  &lt;iframe class=&quot;embed-responsive-item&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_OZa85q0Mzc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;
  &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 22:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/02/22/new-york-new-york-cover-featured-on-cover-and-remix/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.sugardrum.com/blog/2016/02/22/new-york-new-york-cover-featured-on-cover-and-remix/</guid>
        
        
        <category>videos</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
